<review>
    <image><![CDATA[https://cdn1.epicgames.com/offer/bd46d4ce259349e5bd8b3ded20274737/EGS_SpecialEditionContent_TornBannerStudios_AddOn_G1A_04_1920x1080-d471d452a60ac218d54d78778d82d0d3]]></image>
    <title>Chivalry 2</title>
    <rating>5/10</rating>
    <mainGenre>Action</mainGenre>
    <genre>Fighting - Multiplayer</genre>
    <studio>Torn Banner Studios</studio>
    <releaseDate>June 8, 2021</releaseDate>
    <summary>Although the game appears visually appealing, from the gameplay point of view it is hard to enter successfully and it is pretty messy. Playing for a weekend was definitely enough for me to be enough. Somebody might say that the massive fights are messy, but it is the game to be played with a lot of possibilities of actions, thus you have to master them to get better, but how to master so many of them that are pretty much different in any circumstance? No idea. The expectations were much higher than the result obtained.</summary>
    <pros>
        <li>Pretty realistic medieval atmosphere</li>
        <li>Massive fights</li>
        <li>Several game modes</li>
    </pros>
    <cons>
        <li>Combat mechanics are abstract and hard to catch</li>
        <li>High entry threshold</li>
        <li>Animations are not easily distinguishable</li>
        <li>Customisation is mainly not visible</li>
    </cons>
    <po>
        The game appears to be pretty fine from the start. You are welcomed with quite a good performance program that looks good enough. The game proposes you to play a tutorial where you grab all the mechanics necessary to play the game and then you are thrown directly to battle. The atmosphere of tutorial mission and match provides the immersion to feel something resembling the feeling of the battle.
        From the moment of the first real match with a real people you see how many of them there are with you in your team and the opponents: the fights are really massive and even the game modes with lesser number of players involved still support this feeling of massiveness. From my perspective this was supported by the mess that is happening everywhere. Every fight becomes a complete mess in which it is really hard to navigate and analyse. Somebody is fighting, somebody is running around and somebody is just swinging the weapon for no reason, hitting all the allies nearby. The game is pretty much about the team fighting and in such a mess there is no way to make some strategy, at least I do not see that.
        Combat is the core mechanic of the game, as it is basically a fighting genre, but they are pretty much abstract. I would say that the rules are abstract. You get in the mess and that’s it.  Even if you know about what could be done, like hitting an opponent with a farthermost edge of the sword or damaging just when you started the swing. First of all it is impossible to know what the opponent will do and how, as the animations are not also helping, and everybody could jump and turn around like crazy. The game would be better with a specified set of rules that you have a lot of possibilities for correct strikes, but they are limited and the game engages you in the psychological encounter with the opponent and this is where it becomes more interesting. Here, you basically just run around, swing your halberd, damaging your allies and maybe your opponents, as they are blocking, then you are blocking and no one is getting a hit, until his recovery from block is faster or you get killed by your ally or enemies just circled you already. You do not control anything. Sometimes you just defeat another player in a 1v1 fight because he could be faster, has larger range or shorter range or whatever could cause the defeat. As for me, to progress you have to analyse your mistakes, but with limitless possibilities you cannot become better a lot and the game has a pretty high entry threshold, so it is really difficult to start playing and make a positive impact.
    </po>
</review>