<review>
    <image><![CDATA[https://image.api.playstation.com/vulcan/ap/rnd/202207/1308/unR3jprJn4h0yo1W6WBnek6g.jpg]]></image>
    <title>Vampire: the Masquerade - Bloodhunt</title>
    <rating>6/10</rating>
    <mainGenre>Action</mainGenre>
    <genre>Battle-royale - Multiplayer</genre>
    <studio>Sharkmob</studio>
    <releaseDate>April 27, 2022</releaseDate>
    <summary>The game raised way more expectations in my case, but it is an ordinary battle royale with its own additions, where in order to do at least something you would need to be quite proficient in not only the genre, but the game itself. Not the best thing to choose only for a weekend to play, in order to enjoy.</summary>
    <pros>
        <li>Awesome visuals</li>
        <li>Engaging vertical gameplay</li>
    </pros>
    <cons>
        <li>Music during match prevents you from hearing other players</li>
        <li>Inconvenient shooting</li>
        <li>Sliding</li>
        <li>Too high entry threshold</li>
        <li>Extremely quick encounters</li>
        <li>One map</li>
    </cons>
    <po>
        The game welcomes anybody with a stunning cinematic, setting up the expectation about the quality of graphics to a high level and it does not disappoint in any way. The world (only lobby and a map) looks incredible and is extremely detailed. On the map there are points of interest spread everywhere, so you can explore things in your own way. The lobby introduces you to the world, there are different weapons and items on display so you can read about them and get to know everything before encountering it on the battlefield. Moreover, there are some characters that provide you with some knowledge about the lore and give you some quests even though they are pretty basic. A huge amount of work was done on each person in the game, including the cosmetics and the wardrobe, and it feels stunning. A vast range of options on how to customize your characters could make you occupied for a lot of time (but of course you need to unlock the things first).
        From the beginning, you are thrown into a tutorial that provides you with basic knowledge on how to interact with the game. Playing as a vampire you can do plenty of things that look beautifully in combination with visual effects. By doing everything you can feel the power of your character. Although using shooting weapons as a vampire is not what you could expect, being able to combine it with supernatural forces gives a thing. Moreover when you realize that the action may happen not only on one level, but houses of different heights, streets, courtyards, etc. It creates a good first impression.
        However, when you enter the real game, things get much more complicated.
        Firstly, being the game when the one who notices the enemy first could get an advantage, you expect to be hearing them at least a little, so you can prepare. Of course, the sound system is done and you really produce more sound when running or using skills to for instance jump over roofs. But, sometimes the music starts playing from an unknown origin, that looks like a background soundtrack, that is much louder than any simple noise characters could make. The thing is that your opponent may not hear it at all and have more advantage.
        Secondly, as the game is in third person, the character is placed at the side of the camera, so aiming using the middle of the screen when your character is half behind the cover prevents you from shooting there. The gun just points in a wall and shoots in a wall. This is really annoying, especially when there are multiple enemies and in order to shoot you have to fully leave the cover and mostly it does not let you come back alive. Any kind of looking out of the cover would make it better.
        The next thing that is hard to control is sliding. When you are running, you can press crouch and the character will slide forward. This mechanic is necessary because of the high pace of the gameplay. Although it may seem that it is ok when running, when you just move a little and press crouch again, you again slide a mile ahead.
        As expected of any game of the genre, it is difficult to win. However, the game pace is so quick, that it gets too difficult. Every encounter may last a few seconds and because of the verticality of the map, it is almost impossible to predict what will happen. The enemy you are fighting could jump from the roof, while firing in the air, teleport to another roof, get invisible or whatever and take into consideration different heights of roofs, streets, side alleys,… Pretty tough, to say the least.
        And finally, there is only one map. It is not that huge and there are not that many players on it, but it is still one map however beautiful it may look. 
    </po>
</review>