<review>
    <image><![CDATA[https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fall-guys-is-now-free-for-all-on-the-epic-games-store-1920x1080-64479af04272.jpg]]></image>
    <title>Fall Guys</title>
    <rating>7/10</rating>
    <mainGenre>Action</mainGenre>
    <genre>Battle-royale - Multiplayer</genre>
    <studio>Mediatonic</studio>
    <releaseDate> August 4, 2020</releaseDate>
    <summary>The game is extremely fun to play with friends for a couple of hours. On my opinion the game is not that enjoyable when you do that alone, but it is for everybody to decide. It is definitely worth a try.</summary>
    <pros>
        <li>Nostalgic for such TV shows from childhood</li>
        <li>Pretty funny</li>
        <li>Cool coop</li>
        <li>Lots of game modes</li>
        <li>Chaotic in a good way</li>
    </pros>
    <cons>
        <li>After some time it gets repeatable</li>
        <li>Some modes are too much based on luck</li>
        <li>Not precise when it needs to</li>
    </cons>
    <po>
        Everybody who has ever watched or played this game would agree, that it is based on shows that they at some point of their life watched on TV, be it in childhood or adolescence or adulthood. At some point they were quite popular, especially in Japan, and lots of people wanted to try out the experience of participating in one of them, which this game successfully provides the player with. In combination with simple capsule-like characters and goofy animations it brings a lot of fun playing it with your friends. It can be as a solo play, 2-player matches or a squad (this one takes very long time to find). 
        Gathering with friends in Discord and playing those rounds until players get eliminated brings a lot of fun, taking into consideration a vast range of modes and maps. However, at some point you will notice that some of them are more frequent than others (that eventually make the game boring) and some of them appear to be much more difficult that they should. Even if it is pretty simple, you could screw things up just because you have never seen the game mode that was randomly chosen. Good that the game allows you to leave at any point, without the penalty.
        Speaking of different modes, apart from different complexity levels, some of them may be too based on luck and random, which gets frustrating if you play it seriously. Along with the lack of precision, when you want to be as precise as possible. Finally, the arguable thing, that it is extremely chaotic. You may lose because somebody was in front and you did not manage to climb the wall, or flying object just bounces of players or other things in an unexpected trajectory, pushing you into the slime, or you can’t go further as the mob around you is so dense and nobody moves, etc. It seems fun at first, but after some time it gets frustrating.
    </po>
</review>