<review>
    <image><![CDATA[https://gmedia.playstation.com/is/image/SIEPDC/elden-ring-hero-banner-desktop-01-en-24jan22?$3200px$]]></image>
    <title>Elden Ring</title>
    <rating>10/10</rating>
    <genre>Action RPG</genre>
    <studio>FromSoftware</studio>
    <releaseDate>February 25, 2022</releaseDate>
    <summary>Even hearing people complaining that the game is a Dark Souls 4, I can simply say that it is not just a Dark Souls 4. It’s the Dark Souls 4 in open-world, with plot easier to grasp and a combination of the best features and mechanics from previous games. Generally, its not as perfect as DSIII, but taking into consideration me playing the former years after release, and this game just after the first day patch, after some updates it would receive a 10/10.</summary>
    <pros>
        <li>Perfect visual and music</li>
        <li>Spectacular combination of open-world with traditional Soulsborne locations</li>
        <li>Challenging and rewarding combat</li>
        <li>Quests require exploration</li>
    </pros>
    <cons>
        <li>Boss AI frequently gets stuck</li>
        <li>Lots of repetitive bosses</li>
        <li>Some attacks and combos are almost impossible to evade</li>
        <li>Ping in PVP is frustrating</li>
    </cons>
    <po>
        As a tradition, all FromSoftware games stand out from the other project with their own approach to visual style of the world and the music. With each their project it becomes better and better, without losing its unique features. Moreover, their obsession with cloth/hair simulations creates an impression of realistic, living characters, as almost all the parts of their armour and the body reacts to the moves. The magic has come to the new level, with a range of new spells, interesting, although not always practical, as well as the new weapon arts, now called the ashes of war, make even wielding the melee weapon feel showingly impressive.
        The level design is as always interesting, engaging to explore, rewarding for the exploration and, of course, surprising with unexpected danger. Mostly, the locations are open world, where everywhere there are lots of enemies, some ruins, dungeons, caves, etc. Moreover, on all locations they have added different strange animals, which brings a lot of life to the world. However, there are areas that resemble traditional Soulsborne locations, like castles, catacombs, etc. There the level design becomes a maze with difficult enemies, where you cannot just mount a Torrent and ride away.
        The encounters with enemies are difficult, and no matter how high level you have, the game just becomes a little bit easier, but you still have the chances to die, as you did 40 levels before. Of course, the more difficult the encounter, the stronger the enemy, the more runes you obtain and from unique opponents you gain some unique loot, like weapons, armour, spell, etc. So the game not only encourages you to explore the world, but also to fight.
        In  this game, on the contrary to the previous ones,  the quests and lore are not that mysterious. From the dialogues with NPC you can pretty easily grasp what is going on, although it may not be very clear, as still, the idea is to provide every player the possibility to understand the plot his/her own way. But, knowing what is happening, is not like receiving a marker on a map, in order to proceed, you a required to find the place, the NPC was talking about or mentioning and sometimes getting there requires finding the hidden path through the wall, so it even adds a little of complications to the exploration.
        Despite the good overall feeling the game provides, the main disadvantage is that the boss AI, even becoming more “intelligent”, can be easily glitched and just simply spammed with the weapon of your choice. This mostly happens with big enemies, when you conjure the spirits, the boss mostly does not know, what is happening, who it is to attack, etc. This of course makes the game easier, but not in a good way.
        In addition, the great amount of locations require lots of content, and, consequently, lots of bosses. Not telling that there is very little of them, they just are repeated a lot of times, becoming stronger and stronger, and at some point they become simple enemies that are patrolling some ruins in packs. Kind of a lazy approach.
        Apart from the ping in PVP, that makes it impossible to hit an invader and crashes, I found one more disadvantage. It, obviously, is not a frequent case, but mostly the bosses which I can say are unjustifiably difficult, when they tend to use attacks and combos which for me seem impossible to evade. For example the Waterfowl dance of Malenia. Large AoE attacks are faster than any dodge, and no matter when you dodge you will get hit, stunned and in most times killed. This, of course, shouldn’t be a walk, but the attack that the only way to evade is to either block, but its not 100% way of success, or to run away and hope that she wont get you with a corner of a hitbox.
    </po>
</review>